GORDON: Previously on Gotham...
GORDON: I'm arresting you for
the murder of the boy you blew up
under the Crown Point Bridge.
And how can you help me?
What do you say,
pal? Give me a smile...
(LAUGHS)
BRUCE: I'm not who my
parents might've wanted me to be.
- And I'm okay with that.
- I'm not okay with it.
I went to my lawyer to have
him draw up emancipation papers.
Alfred, you're fired.
Now get the hell
out of my house.
I am in control!
But why would you want that?
We had so much
fun when we were me.
- MAN: Surprise.
- (GUN COCKS)
SOFIA: I needed the
police to turn on Penguin.
So you sent this
monster to my city?
(GUNSHOT)
I need you at the
head of the GCPD.
Let them think you're a hero.
This is Gordon. I just
shot and killed the Pyg.
SELINA: Ivy?
What happened to you?
IVY: I've been reborn.
(YELLS AND GROANS)
IVY: And I will never
be underestimated
or ignored ever again.
Let's make Gotham our bitch.
(BUZZER RINGS)
Can I help you?
You're so beautiful.
Thanks.
Now, move.
BOY: Hey, Dad, guess what
happened at school today.
GIRL: Oh, my God,
you're gonna love this.
BOY: Can I just tell him?
GIRL: Wait. No, can I tell him?
BOY: Just let me tell him.
Nice score.
Cindy, who are these two...
Well, what a
charming young lady.
She's so beautiful, Mom.
- That's cool.
- So your perfume
turns people into
your super fans?
Like all good
things, it'll fade.
But until then,
they're mine.
Freeze.
Not bad.
I'll check out the
rest of the house.
My friend thinks
we're here to rob you.
But I know who you work for,
Roland Charles, PhD.
How you torture plants
in the name of science.
Do you ever wonder
how those plants feel?
Soon, you'll share
more with them
than you ever could've imagined.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
What did you do to him?
I gave him what he deserves.
(ROLAND CHOKING)
MAN: Captain, Captain
Gordon. Yoo hoo.
Captain, Captain Gordon.
Chaz Carmichael.
- Congratulations.
- The Boss ain't gonna be happy
I'm in here.
Let's say I got a
lot of responsibility
in my organization.
Well, you seem like
a real responsible guy.
My boss is Sofia Falcone.
Oh, yeah? What's
that got to do with me?
Easy, all I know is, she
told me, if I ever got pinched,
to tell you to give her a call.
Is that so?
You can't do this. I got rights!
Oh yeah, how about you
exercise your right to remain silent?
Hey, Cap.
Got something.
Victim is Roland Charles, over in
R&D, Wayne Enterprises Biotech.
Did you know him from
when you worked at Wayne?
I met him in passing, not that
I recognized him right away.
LUCIUS: It's like the
tweaker we found last week.
The toxin entered
the bloodstream
through the cuts on the neck.
If it is the same as the last
victim, the toxin creates vines
that feed off of
the victim's body,
while also attacking
the hippocampus
like some plant-based
psychedelics.
GORDON: So it kills you
and makes you hallucinate?
- Any witnesses?
- LUCIUS: The family is saying
that it was two women.
Redhead and a brunette.
The redhead used some
kind of hypnosis on them,
and the brunette
wore a leather whip.
Selina Kyle?
Murder's not really her thing.
The family says the
redhead killed Roland.
She left with his briefcase.
If his briefcase is missing,
maybe this is
related to his work
- at Wayne Biotech?
- Doubtful.
He oversaw standard projects,
pharmaceuticals, pesticides.
What?
Nothing.
I'll track down Selina.
(SIGHS)
BRUCE: (ON VOICEMAIL)
This is Bruce. Leave a message.
Bruce, I know we
haven't talked in a while.
But someone just
killed Roland Charles.
We may have a problem.
Roland Charles
asked for clearance
for some top-secret
biotech experiment.
Project M.
Ivy, do you think
I care about that?
You just killed a man
in front of his family.
He had it coming. You have
no idea what these people do.
We need to find out everything
we can about Project M.
And whatever it is,
all access would've had to have
been approved by Bruce Wayne.
You know, I really thought
that doing a crime spree
with you would be fun.
But...
(GRUNTS) I was wrong.
- Selina.
- Leave me alone.
Enjoy your shrubs.
(DOOR CLOSES)
We don't need her.
Now let's show everyone
just how strong we are.
(COCKATOO CROWING)
COCKATOO: Pour me another
shot. Pour me another shot.
(TRILLING)
(WHISTLES)
- Party time.
- (GROANS)
Party time.
- Shut up.
- COCKATOO: Gonna throw up.
Gonna throw up.
IVY: You know, I've
had some crazy nights.
But I've never
bought a talking bird.
Sorry, party's over.
I wasn't at the party.
I've seen you before.
At The Sirens. What
are you doing here?
I'm here to speak for those
who can't speak for
themselves, Bruce.
I'm here to speak
for the plants.
Okay.
My head hurts. Please get out.
First,
tell me about Project M.
How do you know about that?
Oh, I know a lot of things,
billionaire boy.
Ivy?
You're so beautiful.
Now, Project M.
(CROWS CAWING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Hi, guys.
Get it off!
Is this seat taken?
If I say "yes," will it
make a difference?
You know, I've
always been a fan.
When you got locked
up in this loony bin,
I expected great
things, a murder or two,
maybe a prison break.
But all you've done is
mope for the last six weeks.
(WINCES)
You must know I cannot escape.
Why?
None of your business.
(GROANING)
Because Sofia Falcone is holding
someone important to me captive.
And if I escape,
she will kill him.
(YAWNING) Wow,
what a boring story.
If there's one thing I can't
stand, it's someone boring.
The last person who
bored me was Dietrich.
- Dietrich.
- I had to sneak into his shock therapy
session and goose the juice.
Now he pees himself 10 times
a day and sometimes, uh...
Poos himself. (CHUCKLES)
Well, that's very sad.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I'm gonna cure you
of this attitude, Oswald.
I'm gonna find that
entertaining guy
I know is inside of you.
And when I do, ooh,
we are gonna have
so much fun together.
That's quite a story.
Not what I was expecting.
You're just so easy to talk to.
Normally, I'd make this quick
like I did with Roland.
But it's your name
on the company
that murders my
little green friends.
I'm so sorry, Ivy.
I would never want to upset you.
But you have, Bruce.
Hide out here all you want.
Bury your head in the sand.
You're still guilty.
(GASPS)
It'll be slow.
And it'll be painful.
But it's what you deserve.
- (GROANS)
- (BODY THUDS)
(WHEEZING)
I'm just sorry I won't be
here to see you bloom.
(CHOKING)
(GASPING)
Nope, nope.
No. None of these will do.
Where's Ivy?
What did she do
to me? Where am I?
Ah!
Just the thing.
Ra's al Ghul?
Nope, never heard of him.
I'm Dr. Greenthumb, just here
to do a little light pruning, really.
No!
- (WHISTLING)
- (BRUCE SCREAMING)
There.
That's better.
Mummy always used to say,
"A little pruning
encourages growth."
- Where are you taking that?
- Thanks, poppet.
BRUCE: Where are
you taking my face?
Please, what's happening to me?
My dear boy,
you're dying.
Just hold still, while
I put these in place.
- BRUCE: No.
- Good Lord.
(BRUCE SCREAMING)
Jim, what a pleasant surprise.
- I'm looking for Selina.
- Haven't seen her.
She's more of an alley
cat than a house cat.
- Now I'm just in the middle...
- SOFIA: Let him in.
Hello, James.
It's been a while.
Barbara, can you
give us a moment?
Sure.
Have fun, lovebirds.
What is your business
with Barbara Kean?
You're worried that I told
her about our arrangement?
(CHUCKLES) I know
how to keep a secret.
Now, I want my man Carmichael
released from GCPD custody.
That wasn't the deal.
You run the underworld.
I run the GCPD.
Your guy got
arrested. That's on him.
Let me make something clear.
Our deal is
whatever I say it is.
Unless you want people
to know you're responsible
for bringing the Pyg to town.
You brought him to Gotham.
I was just trying
to stop Penguin.
But you covered it up and
took credit for killing him.
Word gets out, you're destroyed,
along with your beloved GCPD.
And if I go down,
so will you.
And I think you like being
Queen of the Underworld.
(SCOFFS) You still think you
know what I will and won't do?
I know a bluff when I see one.
I have a job to do.
GORDON: Selina.
Hey, Jim, I found
Selina. She went that way.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
No! No! No!
INMATE: Shut your beak.
PENGUIN: No, no!
(INMATES CHUCKLING)
(GASPING)
What do you want?
I told you, Pengy.
I'm gonna cure you of
this sad sack mopey act.
And the best cure
is the laughing cure.
(LAUGHTER)
Make me laugh.
INMATES: (CHANTING) Make
him laugh! Make him laugh!
So what'll you be performing?
Contortionism,
juggling act, a tight five?
Oh. What's that?
- You want to do a clown dance?
- (INMATES EXCLAIMING)
- Yeah!
- Wonderful.
I will not!
INMATES: Ooh.
PENGUIN: No.
Get your hands off. No!
INMATES: (CHANTING) Make him
laugh! Make him laugh! Make him laugh!
(SQUEAKER SQUEAKING)
In your own time.
(GRUNTS)
You have no idea
how I've suffered.
The betrayals I've endured.
Just leave me alone.
- (SOBBING) Leave me alone!
- Cut!
(SIGHS)
Oswald, Oswald, Oswald.
You are trapped in a prison
in here.
And I'm offering you the key.
So, dance!
INMATES: (CHANTING) Make him
laugh! Make him laugh! Make him laugh!
Now we're talking.
I can feel the funny
coming. Here it comes!
Here comes the funny. Again!
(SCREAMING)
Fred Astaire, you are not.
I'll try again tomorrow.
(CLAMORING)
What the hell, man?
Why were you running, Selina?
'Cause a jerk with a
badge was chasing me.
So not because you were
in Roland Charles' house
last night when he
was turned into a tree?
His family saw a
redhead and a brunette.
The brunette was carrying
a leather whip just like yours.
Tell me I'm crazy.
I swear, I was only
there to rob the place.
So what about the redhead?
She killed some tweaker in
The Narrows the same way.
I need a name.
(SIGHS) Ivy Pepper.
Try again. I know Ivy.
No, Gordon, she's changed.
Like a lot.
She can use plants to hypnotize
people and poison them.
So why'd she wanna kill Roland?
'Cause he works for
Wayne Enterprises.
Wayne Enterprise?
She's obsessed with a super
secret project they're doing.
Lucius lied.
Come on, let's go.
Admiring my handiwork?
Excuse me?
Look how beautiful he became.
And all it took
was a little scratch.
What do you want from me?
I wanna know about Project M.
- What is Project M?
- Mmm-mmm.
Bruce Wayne told me everything.
How he didn't even trust
himself with the location
but that you know where it is.
And you're gonna take me to it.
But first,
you probably wanna
tell me I'm beautiful.
Yes.
BRUCE: Help.
Help! Somebody help me!
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- (WOMAN CHUCKLING)
Beautiful.
Jim. Jim, you need to help me.
GORDON: Ouch.
Looks like you cut
yourself shaving, old man.
Jim, it's me. It's Bruce.
I'm Bruce Wayne.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Honey, I think we'd know
if you were Bruce Wayne.
He's the one
throwing this shindig.
That's him yonder.
WOMAN: Bruce,
you're incorrigible.
I may bust a gut.
- Luckily, I am a doctor.
- (BOTH LAUGH)
Ain't he the cat's
pajamas? (LAUGHING)
Go on.
Easy there, sport.
It's Italian velvet.
What did you do?
Where's Ra's al Ghul?
Ra's al who?
It's my face.
He gave you my
face. That's my face.
I think you've
been hitting the gin.
Give me back my
face. I'm Bruce Wayne.
Get off of me.
You're ruining my fun.
Everything all right?
- Master Bruce?
- Yes, thank you.
- Just getting rid of the riffraff.
- (CHICKEN CLUCKING)
Dude, what is it with
you and arm-grabbing?
Harper, I need keys to lockup.
And is Lucius in his office?
Lucius? No, he left
with Ivy a little while ago.
- Ivy Pepper? She was here?
- Yeah.
She asked me to
introduce her to everyone.
Isn't she the coolest?
She's a psycho who turned
a guy into a potted plant.
What's going on with you?
Did he just say
that Ivy's a psycho?
But Ivy's the best.
Is this the hypnosis
I've been hearing about?
I'm gonna say yeah.
Until it fades, they'll
do anything for her.
And think she's the coolest.
What do you mean
by, "Ivy's a psycho"?
Hold that thought, Harper.
We'll be right back.
You hear what the
Captain said about Ivy?
- But Ivy's awesome.
- Yeah, she is the coolest.
(DOOR OPENS IN DISTANCE)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(GASPS)
No more! No more!
You have a visitor.
Hello, Oswald.
I see Arkham's
treating you well.
(LAUGHS)
I take it you're here to gloat.
You are correct.
And why not?
I am in an insane asylum,
being pummeled by lunatics.
(CHUCKLING)
Then again,
at least I'm not a moron.
I may not be the man I once was.
But I have many things
that you do not have.
A purpose.
Friends. You have
neither of those.
And I wanted you to see that.
No.
I know you.
There's something else going on.
Something else brought you here.
There's nothing else.
I wanted you to see
how well I am doing.
And I wanted to see
how miserable you are.
Mission accomplished. (CHUCKLES)
Ed.
I'm going to be
out of here soon.
And once I am, I
am going to wipe
that smile off your face.
Preferably with a chainsaw.
Now, how are you
going to do that?
You have no friends,
no one to help you escape.
You are utterly alone.
Goodbye, Oswald.
Sorry, but I don't
put too much stock
in the opinions of simpletons!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
"I am held captive all day,
my brilliance locked away.
"This prison must
be broken. The key?
"My name which must be spoken."
You're still in there.
That's why you came.
You're still there.
And you're gonna help
me find a way out of here.
Hello? We should be leaving.
Not until we find out
where Ivy took Lucius.
There has to be something.
IVY: You know where it is and
you are going to take me to it.
LUCIUS: Mmm.
You're so incredible.
IVY: Uh-huh. Where is Project M?
LUCIUS: Wayne Biotech has
a secret facility outside the city
at the edge of Kane Park.
Good man, Lucius.
COP: In here.
Hey, Cap, the boys
and I were talking,
and we didn't
really like the way
that you were talking about Ivy.
I told you we should've left.
Look, I think you
misinterpreted what I was saying.
You called Ivy a psycho.
That's a term of endearment.
I love Ivy. I think she's great.
What about you?
Do you love Ivy?
Yeah, I love Ivy.
How much?
I love Ivy so much that
I wish I could be her.
You're not really selling it.
And you think you did?
Run.
HARPER: Get them!
Selina!
(SNORING)
(KEY JINGLING)
(DOOR OPENS)
All right, Oswald,
old buddy, old pal.
Tonight, we're gonna cure you.
Make me laugh or else.
Let's call this the
sudden death round.
(SNIFFS)
Dietrich?
(ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
Okay, that was clever-ish.
Yeah, that's a spoon.
It is also a fork!
Looks like you got
some fight in you still.
But it's just too
little, too late, too...
(SIGHS) Boring.
Lobotomize the little bird.
Wait. Wait.
You said this prison
was all in my mind.
Maybe I'm in a prison right now.
A prison where
you can't get to me.
(CHUCKLES)
Okay.
You really are nuts.
(INMATES EXCLAIM)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(FAINT LAUGHTER)
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
Try laughing now,
you ginger sap!
Yes!
(CACKLING)
See? I told you I'd cure you.
Don't flatter yourself!
One more.
(CACKLING)
And so I said to the guy...
You wanna know what I said?
I said, "What is this?
"A three-ring circus?"
(ALL LAUGHING)
And keep them coming.
How long do you think
you can hide in here?
Look.
Out there.
He's going to find
you eventually.
I don't understand.
Who's going to find me?
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
Alfred?
Special Agent Pennyworth
to you, you scumbag!
The kid's secured,
requesting extraction.
No!
Just be careful, here.
We're gonna go this way.
This way.
So this is it.
Project M.
Also called "Lazarus Water."
It belonged to a man
known as Ra's al Ghul.
It stimulates cell growth
at an alarming rate.
We've yet to figure out how.
I assumed Project M killed
plants, but it's the opposite.
Just like humans to lock
up something so beautiful.
What are you
going to do with it?
I'm going to make
miracles happen.
Release me!
Listen to me. I'm Bruce Wayne. I
can pay you whatever you want.
You need to let me go now!
Sorry, I can't do
that now, love.
- You see, I have a mission.
- What mission?
For me to bring you to him.
What is that?
Well, giddy up, son.
What do you want?
Why did you bring me here?
This is where my
parents were killed!
SHADOW: No.
This is where I was born.
No!
That's far enough.
Jim Gordon.
Ivy Pepper.
IVY: It's been a long time.
I'm not the same
kid you remember.
The kid who's father
you and you partner killed
all those years ago?
How is this possible?
Well, first, I was a seed.
Then a sprout.
Now I've bloomed.
Drop your gun.
Or your friend Lucius
becomes a flower arrangement.
Lucius, you okay?
I'm in the sweet embrace of
one of my favorite people, Jim.
Never been better.
Now I know you're tenacious,
Jim Gordon, gun or no gun.
You'll come after me.
But then,
Bruce Wayne will die.
What have you done to him?
I went to Wayne Manor
and planted a seed.
I imagine he's about to bloom.
But if you let me go,
you may have a chance
to get him the antidote.
This isn't over.
You have no idea
how right you are.
I love you.
Lucius, give me the antidote.
Let's just wait until Ivy
is at a safe distance.
Give me the antidote. Come on.
- Don't make me hit you.
- Jim.
I must warn you, I'm
a black belt in jiu-jitsu.
Since when?
Night classes.
- The Lazarus Water.
- Come on.
We've got to get to
Bruce Wayne. Let's go.
(BATS SQUEAKING)
Help!
Somebody help!
(WINGS FLAPPING)
Who's there?
(SQUEAKING CONTINUES)
Show yourself!
Who are you?
SHADOW: I am the
one you cannot escape.
The one you cannot kill.
You're me?
- Please...
- SHADOW: You're scared.
You should be.
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
It's okay, Bruce.
It's all right.
You're safe now.
According to Lucius,
Ivy's toxin attacks the
brain like a hallucinogen.
So whatever you went through,
I doubt it was pleasant,
but it wasn't real.
I think I saw who I really am.
I know what you're gonna say.
But what I saw, it was real.
Well, then you're lucky.
Most people go their
whole lives not ever knowing
- who they really are...
- I'm not lucky.
You didn't see it.
I've seen my own darkness.
I'll say this.
You have people around
you who care for you.
Don't fight this alone.
Trust us.
I'll leave men outside tonight.
I'll come by tomorrow,
check in on you.
Jim.
When I was under,
I saw you.
You had a mustache.
Well, clearly, that's a
very dangerous toxin.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
Alfred, it's...
It's me. It's Bruce. I...
I need your help, Alfred.
Please call me.
- (THUNDER RUMBLING)
- (RAIN PATTERING)
We're not hypnotized.
Just embarrassed.
Good to have you back.
All right, listen up.
I want an APB on Ivy Pepper.
- Finding her is our top priority.
- (CELL PHONE RINGING)
All right, you heard him,
people. Let's get to work.
- What do you want?
- SOFIA: I thought about what you said.
How if I used the Pyg to destroy
you, I'd also destroy myself.
GORDON: And?
And
you're right.
I've come to enjoy being
the Queen of Gotham.
Glad we understand each other.
SOFIA: Not quite. You see, I
also realized I don't need the Pyg.
There are other ways
for me to hurt you.
Thank you so much for coming.
I thought we were
overdue for a chat.
How could I say no
to my sister-in-law?
(RAIN PATTERING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
JOKER: So I strangled
him with his lower intestines.
Relax, buddy.
You gave me what I needed.
The laugh of the century.
Tell me something.
You appear to have everyone
here under your thumb,
- the guards, the inmates...
- What can I say?
I'm a charismatic guy.
You could escape anytime.
- Why stay?
- Hmm.
Why indeed?
- You're planning something.
- JOKER: Righty, old boy.
Something spectacular.
See, I'm in this funny farm
'cause I need to find
the crème de la crazy,
which is why I need you.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Ah, you get it.
But when we're done,
the world out there,
that'll be the asylum.
What do you say?
Thank you for your kind offer.
I don't expect to
be here very long.
You'll come around.
They always do.
(WHISTLING)
Nope.
Where did these
plants come from?
Get out!
Before we call the police.
(COUGHING)
Oh, friends.
You're all so beautiful.
English - SDH